Mss.Rec.30 Mss.Rec.30
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Goodbys, 1954-08-22; 10-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:48; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; Charley, Lemy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; John, Steven; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "The whole group says goodby into the microphone."
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Farewells; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Identification of recording, 1954-08-31; 10-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Frederica de Laguna identifies previously recorded songs and the present occasion. Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
    Indians of North America--Yukon--Music; Klukshu (Yukon)
  - Going to Dalton Post, 1954-08-31; 10-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; Allen, Jessie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "This is a Wolf moiety song. It was composed by a half-breed boy, John Brown (or Broon), Charley's brother, from Champagne, on the occasion of a big potlatch at Bee Lake, to which the original words of the song refer. It was sung to us when we were walking to Dalton Post." Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
    Indians of North America--Yukon--Music; Klukshu (Yukon); Southern Tutchone language
  - Love Song, 1954-08-31; 10-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Allen, Jessie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "Words of song: titl'akwAdzEn' kwAdr'.li' dzEn'ada tEdzEnikwana. A lady get story from her boy friend. She feel sorry for her boyfriend. 'When I hear that story, I feel sorry.' She feel sick about it. She's dead. This is a Wolf song. The composer (? or singer?) was Susie, married to Nelson at one time. Her name was `ntcInulyan`." Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
    Indians of North America--Yukon--Music; Klukshu (Yukon); Love songs; Southern Tutchone language
  - Tlingit Song to dakl'awedi-yAtx'i, 1954-08-31; 10-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Hume, Lily; McClellan, Catharine
    "The song is sung by a Wolf man to Crow girl, nIsAdi-yAtx'i." Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
    Indians of North America--Yukon--Music; Klukshu (Yukon); Tlingit Indians--Music; Tlingit language
  - Tlingit Song to tlukwaxAdi-yAtx'i, 1954-08-31; 10-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Hume, Lily; McClellan, Catharine
    "Words mean: 'When I die, I'm gonna come back, shake your hand.'" Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
  - False start on song by Jessie Allen, 1954-08-31; 10-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Allen, Jessie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
    Farewells; Indians of North America--Yukon--Music; Klukshu (Yukon); Southern Tutchone language
  - Goodby Song for Kitty, 1954-08-31; 10-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; Allen, Jessie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "Words mean: 'My uncle, I don't know where you stay now' like a love song.... When you leave here I gonna be sorry." Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
  - Big Jim's Tlingit Song, 1954-08-31; 10-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Hume, Lily; McClellan, Catharine
    "This is her father's song. He hears bad luck like thunder inside. He hears it that time he start the song. His wife gonna die, his daughter's dead, and his son's wife's dead. Three die in one day. Quick sick. It was at Dalton Post, before the white men came. He heard it (the portent?) down the Alsek at a hil, Sheep Hat, near nuqa-ik." Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.
  - Harry Joe's Mother's mother's brother's Sorry Song, 1954-08-31; 10-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:48; Allen, Jessie; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Hume, Lily; Joe, Harry; McClellan, Catharine
    "Jessie Allen explained: This song was composed (?) by Harry Joe's mother's mother's brother, a Crow man. It's a sorry song for the d as. [sic] He feels bad and is calling for something. People were hunting sheep on top of the mountain. Sit down and think about girl friend (father's sister and cross-cousin). She explained that she was singing the song for Harry Joe because he didn't know it." Recorded at Beloud's, near Klukshu, Yukon Territory.